（ナレーション）
使い捨てられた人工衛星
Abandoned artificial satellites.
Tanks jettisoned from shuttles.
シャトルが切り離したタンク
Debris generated during
space station construction.
ステーション建造時に出た廃棄物
宇宙に浮かぶ たくさんのゴミ
This vast amount of junk floating in space,
space debris, is a very serious threat.
スペースデブリは
実は とても危険な存在です
2075年―
This is a story of 2075, a time in which
this space garbage has become a problem.
これは 宇宙のゴミが
問題になった時代の物語
This is the last of it,
right, Senpai?
（タナベ）
これで最後ですよね？ 先輩
ん？
Go to a private
channel?
プライベートで？
（タナベ）
先輩 ないしょ話ですか？
You want to tell me something in secret,
Senpai?
If you want to badmouth our bosses...
上司の悪口の…
- It's not that!
（ハチマキ）そんなんじゃねーよ
（タナベ）ん？
（ハチマキ）ああ いや
その… タナベ お前さ
I, uh... Tanabe, I was wondering...
Are you, um, seeing anybody?
決まった相手とかいるのか？
（タナベ）えっ あの…
それって どういう意味ですか？
Huh? Um... What do you
mean by that?
（ハチマキ）分かれよ それぐらい
恋人は いるかってことだろ？
Come on, do I have to spell it out for you?!
I'm asking if you have a boyfriend!
I knew that.
That isn't what I meant.
わ… 分かってますよ
そういうことじゃなくて
その…
I...
（ハチマキ）
タナベ ちょっと待った
Tanabe!
Hold that thought!
後ろ 軌道保安庁
Behind you!
It's the OSA!
えっ？
（ハチマキ）
巡視船が何の用だってんだ？
I wonder what that
patrol ship wants with us?
タナベ 下手に動くなよ 捕まるぞ
Don't make any funny moves, Tanabe.
They'll arrest us.
（タナベ）そんな…
You're kidding!
（ハチマキ）最近は物騒だからな
宇宙防衛戦線とかよ
Things have been pretty hairy lately,
what with the Space Defense Front and all.
あっ…
わあっ
すごい １回転
Oh, wow... He stopped
on a dime.
俺たちは ただのデブリ屋だ
何も悪いことは…
We're simple debris haulers.
We haven't done anything...
（ギガルト）
早合点するな ハチマキ
Never jump to conclusions,
Hachimaki.
（ハチマキ）ああ？
（ギガルト）教えたろ
Didn't I teach you that?
宇宙の男は決断を早く
A spaceman makes his decisions quickly,
but very, very carefully.
だが 慎重にしろとな
Sensei!
♪～
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
♪幾千の朝に
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪光が向かう場所へ
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
Phase 9
Regrets
軌道保安庁の
ギガルト･ガンガラガッシュだ
Gigalt Gungulgash of the
Orbital Security Agency.
今日から５日間
保安指導を行うことになった
For the next five days, I will be conducting
security training exercises with you.
I look forward to
working with you.
よろしく頼む
N-No, sir!
The pleasure is all ours!
こ… こちらこそ
よろしく お願いします
It's good to see you
again, Gigalt-san.
（ユーリ）
お久しぶりです ギガルトさん
（タナベ）え？
（課長）懐かしいね ガンちゃん
It's just like old times, Gan-chan.
How are things at the OSA?
保安庁は どう？
（ギガルト）おう
１人 掘り出し物がいてなあ
Great. A real diamond in the rough just
joined up. I'm grinding down his rough edges.
今 みっちり仕込んどる
That diamond in the rough
has my sympathies.
（フィー）
その掘り出し物に同情するわ
ハハハハ…
よっ 砂時計
Hello there, Hourglass!
You still hitting the books?
勉強は ちゃーんとしてるか？
（エーデル）ええ とっても
Yes, sir.
Hitting them hard.
（タナベ）はあ…
タナベ ギガルトは
２年前まで うちにいたのよ
Tanabe, Gigalt worked here
up until two years ago.
（ハチマキ）
失礼のないように気をつけろよ
So don't do anything
to insult him!
俺に宇宙のことを
教えてくれた人なんだからな
He's the man who taught me
everything I know about space.
Oh, so that's why you
call him "Sensei."
ああ それで先生って
Sorry for scaring you back there, little lady.
I'm Hachimaki's sensei.
さっきは どうも お嬢さん
ハチマキの先生です
あ… あっ はい 田名部(たなべ) 愛(あい)です
Y-Yes, sir!
I'm Tanabe Ai!
先輩にも 先生がいたんですね
So you had a sensei, too,
huh, Senpai?
当たり前だ！
Of course I did!
Let's have a welcome party!
On the company's tab, of course!
（ラビィ）歓迎会やりましょ
もちろん 会社の経費で
（ユーリ）
ギガルトさん もう公務員ですよ
Gigalt-san is a
public servant now.
あっ 接待禁止か
Oh, so no wining
and dining, huh?
You're the same as ever,
Sunflower.
相変わらずだな ヒマワリは
Have you seen Sunflower's ultimate
party trick, little lady?
お嬢さんは もう見たかい？
ヒマワリの必殺芸
ヒマワリ？
Sunflower?
ラビィのことだよ
He means Lavie.
フィーが“ターボライター”で
課長は“マシュマロ”
Fee is Turbo Lighter.
The Chief is Marshmallow.
名前を覚えるのは苦手でね
I'm not too good at remembering names, so I
give people nicknames that I can remember.
だから あだ名を付けて覚える
まっ 定着したのは
ハチマキだけだったが
But it looks like "Hachimaki"
is the only nickname that stuck.
えっ ハチマキって
ギガルトさんが付けたんですか
You're the one who gave him
the name Hachimaki, Gigalt-san?
（ギガルト）
おう いつまでも“新入り”じゃ
かわいそうだからな
Yeah. I felt bad calling him
"rookie" all the time.
（ハチマキ）ああっ
（タナベ）新入り…
Rookie...
くっ 何だよ
何か文句でもあるのか？
What, you got a problem
with that?
（ゲイハート）
本日より１か月間―
For the next month, we will be hosting these
four security instructors from the OSA.
軌道保安庁から この４名の
保安指導員を受け入れます
各部署を順に視察し―
They will observe each
department in turn.
君たち管制課Ｂ班は
２週間後の予定です
You of Control Section Group B are
scheduled for two weeks from now.
However, the instructors will be
on company grounds at all times,
…が 指導員は
常に社内にいるので―
全員法令を順守し
言動には十分 留意するように
...so obey all regulations scrupulously and pay
close attention to what you say and do.
（ドルフ）保安庁からの
軌道保全業務監査の対応は頼めるな
I assume I can count on you to provide our
report for the Orbital Security Operating Audit?
（ゲイハート）
あっ… いや 私は―
Well, um, I have to work out
next quarter's work orbits, so...
来期の業務軌道を
取りまとめねばなりませんし
And I still have those contract
drafts to prepare...
（社員１）私も契約書のドラフトが
残ってまして
（社員２）
月末の請求書の締め切りが…
And the the end-of-month
billing deadline is coming up.
（クレア）
私にやらせてください
Let me see to it, sir.
うあっ 君は タンデムミラー関係の
搬送作業があるだろう
But you're overseeing all the shipping related
to the tandem mirror project, aren't you?
大丈夫です やらせてください
I can handle it, sir.
Let me take care of it.
（ゲイハート）う… うーん…
分かった この件は君に頼もう
All right. I'll leave
the matter to you.
分かった この件は君に頼もう
えっ？
はい
Thank you, sir.
The arrival of GO-44
will be delayed...
（チェンシン）ああ ごめんね
その日は予定が入ってて
I'm sorry, I have plans
that day.
（リュシー）あっ… ん…
チェンシンさんって
彼女いないんですよね？
Cheng-Shin-san, you don't have
a girlfriend, right?
いないけど
気になっている子はいるかな
I don't, but there's a girl
that I'm interested in.
それって タナベですか？
This girl...
Is it Tanabe?
あっ…
うん
救命ボールに爆弾を仕掛けるのが
最近の宇宙防衛戦線のやり口です
Planting explosives in rescue balls is
the Space Defense Front's latest M.O.
Note: 'M.O.' is short for Modus operandi, Latin for 'mode of operation'.
Always remember
to inspect them.
常に検査を怠らないでください
自分たちの使う道具です
These are the tools of your trade. Make sure
you conduct one last check yourselves.
最後は
必ず自分でチェックするように
Too slow! I want to see you do it in under
10 minutes without using a dressing frame!
（ギガルト）
遅い！ 着脱支援具なしで
10分は切りなさい！
（ハチマキ）
服の慣性に合わせんだよ！
Work with the suit's inertia!
お前は６分でやれぃ！
（ハチマキ）あっ はい
- I want you to do it in six!
Yes, sir!
（ギガルト）
分かったな 常に太陽の位置を―
Got it? Keep the sun's position
memorized at all times!
頭に入れておくんだ
（ハチマキ･タナベ）はい
Yes, sir!
げえっ
（ギガルト）野菜を取れと―
How many times do I have to tell you
to eat your vegetables?
何度 言ったら分かるんだ
ちょっと 先生
Aw, c'mon, Sensei!
（ギガルト）
ハチマキ 俺に逆らうたあ…
Hachimaki, you must think you're hot stuff,
trying to fight me like this...
（ハチマキ）
何言ってんすか この～
What're you talking about...?
Why, you...!
んぐぅ… くぅ…
Hachi!
（ラビィ）ハチ いけ！
（課長）ガンちゃん
Gan-chan!
（ギガルト）ぐああっ…
（ラビィ）いけ ハチ ハチ
（ハチマキ）うわーっ
（課長）やっほー！
うっしゃー！
Boo-yah!
ちっくしょう
フェイントなんて汚ねえぞ
Son of a...
That was dirty, using a feint!
This is about brute force! Brute force!
実力で勝負しろ 実力で
Okay, let's start from the top shelf.
Six maintenance packs...
（ハチマキ）やっぱり
全然 変わってないな 先生
Boy, Sensei hasn't
changed one bit.
（タナベ）初めての仕事で
先輩を助けてくれたのって―
So it was Gigalt-san who saved your life
on your first mission, huh, Senpai?
ギガルトさんだったんですね
Yeah. After I had my accident,
I was totally terrified of space.
ああ 俺 事故ったとき
本気で宇宙は怖いって思ってさ
それでも
この仕事を続けてるのは―
The one thing that let me
keep working this job...
先生が宇宙のいいところも
いっぱい教えてくれたからだ
...was that Sensei taught me about lots
of good things space has to offer.
いい先生ですね
He must have been
a great teacher.
（ハチマキ）ああ だから 俺
先生には感謝してるし 尊敬してる
Yeah, that's why I feel so indebted to him
and respect him the way I do.
単に すげえ宇宙飛行士だからって
ことじゃなくて―
It's not just because he's some
astronaut superman or something.
何つーか その… 大事なんだな
He's... I dunno.
He means a lot to me.
あ…
That's it.
よろしく お願いします
（ハチマキ）あ…
Please do the
same for me.
だって 私の先生は先輩でしょ？
Well, you're my sensei,
right, Senpai?
うっ バ… バカ！
先生ってのはな―
G-Get serious!
It takes a guy a lot more amazing
than me to be a sensei.
もっと すげーやつがやるもんだ
（タナベ）フッ…
あの… 先輩
こないだの話ですけど
Um, Senpai... About what
you asked earlier...
（ハチマキ）何だ？
Yeah?
私に その…
つきあってる人がいるかって
You asked, um... You asked
if I was seeing anybody.
（ハチマキ）いるのか？
Are you?
いないです
No, I'm not!
（ハチマキ）そっか
Oh...
いないのか そっか
Oh, so you aren't... I see.
（人々の話し声）
（フィー）ローランドさんですか？
Roland-san?
（ギガルト）
ああ 最近 連絡取れなくてな
Yeah. I haven't been able to
get in touch with him lately.
お前 会ったことなかったっけ？
Right, you never met him,
did you?
ハチマキじゃないが
俺の先生のようなものだ
I don't mean to sound like Hachimaki,
but Roland-san is like my own sensei.
ローランドさんは
亡くなりました 先月
He passed away
last month.
うん！？ あっ…
（フィー）
私とハチが みとったんです
Hachi and I... were with him
when he died.
事故か？
An accident?
No. Suicide.
Or something like it.
いえ 自殺… のようなものです
白血病で
宇宙にいられなくなると気にして
He was worried that he'd be kept out
of space because he had leukemia.
白血病…
Leukemia...
そうか
I see.
分からんものだな 人ってやつは
You just never know it's gonna
turn out with people, do you?
And now, everyone, let's have a toast
to Mr. Gigalt's continued health!
それでは 皆さん
ミスター ギガルトの
ますますのご健勝を祈って
Cheers!
（一同）かんぱーい
ぷはー
すみません 歓迎会が
結局 お別れ会になっちゃって
We're really sorry that your welcome party
ended up being a farewell party.
でも あと ひと月は
セブンにいるんでしょ？
But you're gonna be on Seven
for another month, right?
次は整備課でしたよね
Your going to Maintenance Section next, right?
I wouldn't be saying my goodbyes just yet.
We still have tomorrow's mission.
別れの挨拶は まだ早いぞ
あしたのミッションも残ってる
（ラビィ）
レディース アンド ジェントルメン
Ladies and gentlemen!
本日は アルヴィンド･ラビィが
お送りする―
I would like to bid you welcome to
Arvind Lavie's palace of illusions!
魅惑の殿堂にようこそ
まずは新商品
風船ノーラ君を使った新技
Now may I present my latest trick which utilizes Balloon Nora, on sale at stores everywhere!
ロケットノーラ君を
ご覧くださーい
Behold... Rocket Nora-kun!
（一同の歓声）
（課長）わあっ
（フィーとタナベの笑い声）
Hey, watch it!
おーい おいおい うっ…
フッ…
（一同）ああ…
（ラビィ）もう飲めません…
I can't drink
another drop...
あの… 飲み過ぎじゃないですか？
Um, don't you think you've
had too much to drink?
そんなことはない
ハキム もう１杯
No, I'm doin' fine.
Hakim, top me off.
ハハッ ハキムって
誰のこと言ってんです？
Who're you callin' Hakim?
I'm Hachimaki, remember...?
ハチマキですよ
それより
弱くなったんじゃないんですか？
You don't seem to be able to hold
your booze like you used to, Sensei...
先生
Hachimaki... How are things going
with you and Swan-san?
ハチマキ
お前 白鳥(はくちょう)さんとは―
どうなってるんだ？
（タナベ）え？
What're you talking about,
Sensei?
ん… 何言ってんですか？ 先生
白鳥さんって？
Who's Swan-san?
Isn't it about time you found
a woman and settled down?
そろそろ
身を固めたらどうだ？
Who's this "Swan-san" person?!
白鳥さんって？
管制課の子だ 同期の
That girl in Control Section.
The one who joined the same time as...
クレアさんですか？
You mean Claire-san?!
Yeah, that was
her name...
ああ… そんな名前だった
She and Sempai are going out?
They're an item?!
先輩は つきあってるんですか？
クレアさんと
Don't ask the man
stuff like that!
そんなこと先生に聞くなよ
So tell me, aren't you?!
じゃあ 違うんですか？
（ハチマキ）どっちでもいいだろ？
It's not like it matters
either way...
よくないですよ
私には聞いたじゃないですか？
Yes it does!
You asked me the same question, remember?!
So give me a straight answer!
ちゃんと答えてください！
昔のことだ もう別れた
That's ancient history... We broke up.
いいだろ？ それで
There. You happy now?
ん…
んん…
ウーン…
（社員）来週から
うちにも保安庁の指導員が来るから
One of the OSA instructors will be coming
to our section next week, so be ready.
（リュシー）窮屈そうですね
別に保安指導なんて…
It seems like a formality.
I don't see why we need security...
あっ リュシー たらいまー
Hey, Lucie, I'm home...
タナベ 飲んでるの？
Tanabe, have you
been drinking?
We were having a farewell party
for Senpai's sensei...
（タナベ）
先輩の 先生の お別れ会
（社員）それじゃ
- See you.
（タナベ）
先輩の 先生の お別れ会
あっ はい
- Bye.
（タナベ）
先輩の 先生の お別れ会
みんな 潰れるまで…
We drank 'til we dropped...
ねえ タナベ
Say, Tanabe?
（タナベ）はーい
Yeah?
フライトから戻ったら
話したいことがあるんだけど
There's something I'd like to talk to you
about once my flight gets back.
あっ 私も聞きたいこと…
I wanted to ask you
something, too...
（リュシー）何？
（タナベ）うっ ううっ…
Like what?
タナベ！
Tanabe!
Um... It can wait until your
flight gets back.
（タナベ）えーっと…
フライトから戻ってからでいいや
（リュシー）そう
You sure?
（タナベ）
うん なんだかグルグルー
Yeah...
It feels like the
room is spinning...
何がグルグルだか
You're the one
who's spinning.
（アナウンス）
レギュラーシフトの皆さん―
Good morning to all regular shift crew workers.
All ISPV-7 stations will now begin...
おはようございます
（タナベ）
あっ おはようございます
Good morning, sir!
Wow, you're here early!
お早いですね
Good morning.
You get the booze out of your system?
おはよう 酒は抜けたかい？
Yes, sir! I hit the sauna.
I passed the alcohol check and everything!
はい サウナに入って―
アルコールチェックも
パスしましたから
Okay, that's good.
（ギガルト）よし それでいい
…で ハチマキはどうした？
So, where's Hachimaki?
（タナベ）先輩なら
ハチマキを取りに戻って…
Senpai went back
for his hachimaki.
ああ こっちのほうです
This one, I mean.
ハハハハ…
格好つけてるつもりなんでしょうか
あのハチマキ
I suppose he wears that
hachimaki to look tough,
...but it's not like anybody
can see it in his spacesuit.
宇宙服 着たら見えやしないのに
スイッチなんだよ ありゃあ
It acts as a switch
for him.
え？
He uses that hachimaki to put himself
in the proper frame of mind.
（ギガルト）
あいつはハチマキを使って
自分の気持ちを切り替えてるんだ
（タナベ）
あっ 確かに仕事になると―
Now that you mention it, he does seem
a lot more serious when he's on the job.
すごく真面目になります
（ギガルト）仕事だけじゃない
プライベートもそうだ
Not just on the job.
In his off-hours, too.
こう 自分の頭を縛っちまって
軌道変更が利かないんだなあ
He ties it around his head, and then
nothing can make him change course.
仕事だから
こうしなくちゃいけない
"It's my job, so this
is what I have to do",
...or "I'm a man, so this is something
I'm not allowed to do."
男だから やってはいけないってな
はい 分かります
Yes, sir!
I get it now!
ハチマキをしてるからって
安易に付けた名前じゃあないぞ
I didn't give him that nickname simply
because he wears a hachimaki headband.
（タナベ）おみそれしました
Yes, sir, I never
thought of that!
ハハハハ…
あの… 聞いてもいいですか？
Um... Can I ask you
something?
（ギガルト）ん？
その… クレアさんは
どうして白鳥なんですか？
About Claire-san... Why did you
give her the nickname "Swan"?
ええ？
Oops. Maybe I shouldn't
have said anything.
ああ…
余計なことを言っちまったかな
（タナベ）
あの… 言えないことでしたら
Um... If you can't tell me,
I'll understand.
Well, it's... You know how swans look all elegant
and graceful as they glide along the water?
いや ほら 白鳥ってのは―
優雅に水面を
進んでるみたいに見えるだろう？
けど 水の下じゃあ
必死に足で水をかいてるんだ
Under the water, though, their legs
are paddling away like crazy.
あっ… はあ
Oh...
That Swan lady pushes
herself too hard.
（ギガルト）
いろいろと無理してるのさ
あの白鳥さんは
（キーボードを打つ音）
Claire-kun.
When can I expect to see that plan
for the OSA?
保安庁向けのプラン
いつ もらえるかな？
（クレア）はい
Yes, sir. I'll have it to you
by the end of the day.
今日中には必ず
（ゲイハート）
君が自分から言いだしたんだからね
You're the one who volunteered to do it,
so don't expect any help from me.
私は手伝わないよ
はい 大丈夫です
Yes, sir.
I can handle it.
（キーボードを打つ音）
（タナベ）今日のデブリって
私と同い年なんですよ
Our debris today is the same age as me.
打ち上げのちょうど１か月後が…
（フィー）ああ？
I was born exactly one month after it was launched.
- Why am I getting a heat source
off the debris?
なんで デブリに熱源が…
（電子音）
（フィー）はっ ２つ？
There are two?
Huh? I don't get it.
えっ… どうして？
（ハチマキ）フィー
（フィー）分かってる
Fee.
Yeah, I know.
（ユーリ）アームを出します
（ギガルト）急げよ
I'll deploy the arm.
Hop to it.
何なんですか？ 一体
What the heck
is going on?
Every once in a while,
you run into guys like this.
（フィー）
たまにいるのさ こんなやつらが
あっ 他のデブリ屋さんですか？
Are they another
debris team?
（ハチマキ）俺たちと反対のな
Yeah, but the
opposite of us.
（タナベ）反対？
The opposite?
（ギガルト）使用済み核燃料や
産業廃棄物なんかを―
They come up here into space and dump stuff
like expended atomic fuel or industrial waste.
宇宙に捨てていく連中だ
単に捨てるだけだと
センサーに引っ掛かるからな
If they just dumped it, sensors
would detect it right away.
だから ああして １つのデブリに
見えるように くっつけてるんだ
So they attach it to another piece of debris
to make it look like it's all one big piece.
（タナベ）それって もしかして
犯罪じゃないんですか？
Hey, wait a minute...
Isn't that illegal?!
だから とっ捕まえてやるんだよ
Which is why we're
gonna nab 'em!
（クレア）
不法投棄？ よりによって監査中に
Illegal dumping? Why did they have
to do it during our security audit?
Hey! Contact the OSA!
（管制官）おい 保安庁に連絡を
（クレア）分かっています
I'm on it!
You're not getting away
from me!
逃がすか この！
うっ… 捕まえた
Okay, gotcha!
（電子音）
よーし そこまでだ 愚か者ども
Okay, that'll be enough of that, you morons!
こちらは軌道保安庁の…
This is the INTO Orbital Security Agency!
（作業員）うるせえ バカ！
（ギガルト）ああっ？
- You're not fooling
anybody, jerk!
You think a bunch of junk
jockeys can catch us?!
（作業員）デブリ屋が
俺たちを捕まえられるかっての
Are they gonna try to manually
cut our arm loose?
あいつら
人力でアームを切り離す気？
ほう
やる気は買ってやろう だがな
If you want a fight, we'll give you one.
But...
ハチマキ！
Hachimaki!
Let's do it, Sensei!
はい 先生
（作業員１）港湾接舷用の
大型マニピュレーターに―
This thing's got a jumbo arm that's supposed to
be used for docking, and even a gantry crane!
ガントリークレーンたあ
何なんだよ この船
What kind of ship
is this?!
（作業員２）動力ケーブル 探せ
Look for the power cable!
Get the cutters!
（船長）オンボロ船のアームなんざ
とっとと切り離せ！
Cut loose that piece
of crap's arm!
If we get caught, we're looking
at 20 years at hard labor!
捕まったら 懲役20年は食らうぞ
Our active stealth
is working, right?
アクティブスレスは効いてるな
The phase shifter
is functioning.
（船員）
フェーズシフター 作動しています
よーし 保安庁が来る前に片づける
Okay! Finish up before
the OSA gets here!
Why can't I?
I want to go, too!
（タナベ）
どうして駄目なんですか？
私も行きます
I told you, this is
no place for a rookie!
（ハチマキ）だから
新入りは引っ込んでろっての
こういうのに
新入りも先輩もないと思います
I don't think this is a time for worrying
about who's a rookie or who's a senpai!
（ハチマキ）
命綱 付けてられないのに
足手まといなんだよ！
You can't use a lifeline this time!
You'll just get in the way!
（タナベ）うわあああーっ
先生 俺たちのコンビを
やつらに見せつけてやりましょう
Sensei! Let's show 'em what
a team like you and I can do!
（ギガルト）ハチマキ
（ハチマキ）はい
Hachimaki!
Sir?
宇宙の男なら 女には手を上げるな
Nobody who calls himself a spaceman
ever raises his hand to a woman.
うっ…
尻です
It was my butt.
Hurry it up, damn it!
Finish up!
（作業員１）
とっとと片づけろ とっととよ
Cut this thing loose!
（作業員２）さっさと切り離せ
It's pretty tough.
（作業員２）結構 頑丈だな
（作業員３）相当 古い船だぞ
今どき こんなアーム使わない
This ship is pretty old.
Who uses an arm like this these days...
（ハチマキ）ええいっ
（作業員２）
うおっ デブリ屋が やる気か？
Oh, you wanna start
something, junk man?
うおっ
おわあっ
向こうからも出てきた？
They sent out some
people, too, huh?
はい
２人だけですが押されています
Yes, sir. There's only two of them,
but we're being driven back.
何やってる！
こっちは７人もいるんだぞ
What are our guys doing?!
We've got seven people out there!
Everybody who isn't busy,
get out there, and...
手の空いてるやつ 全員外に
おっ 何だ？ 船まで動かして
What the...?
They're moving their ship, too?
DS-12, this is Seven.
（クレア）DS-12 こちらセブン
現在 軌道保安庁の巡視船が
そちらに向かっています
An INTO Orbital Security Agency patrol vessel
is currently en route to your position!
あんまり危険なことは…
Don't try anything danger-
（フィー）それが来るまで
待ってられないんだよ
- These guys won't wait until that patrol boat shows up!
巡視船の軌道データを回して
Forward the ship's
orbital data to me!
このまま
保安庁に突き出してやる！
We're gonna march these bozos
straight to the OSA!
（船員）
駄目です 引っ張られます
It's no use!
We're being dragged along!
たかが デブリ回収船のくせに―
What the hell is a debris hauler doing
with an engine that powerful?!
なんて でかいエンジン
積んでやがんだ おい！
Hey! Haven't you gotten
that arm off us yet?!
まだ アームは外せねえのか
（作業員１）
型が古すぎて無駄にでかい…
It's an old model, so it's
way bigger than it needs to...
（ハチマキ）
えいっ 悪かったな 古くてよ
Well pardon us
for being so old!
なっ うっ… 接着材？
Adhesive?
廃棄物を
デブリにくっつけてたやつか
Must be what they were using
to stick their waste to the debris!
（作業員２）今更 捕まるわけには
いかねえんだよ！
We're not gonna let you
take us in, not now!
でやーっ うう… うっ
（ギガルト）殺人未遂
これで 25年は追加だな
Attempted murder.
That's an additional 25 years.
Then I don't have anything
to lose, do I?!
（作業員２）
だったら いっそのことー！
ぬうううっ…
You dumb bastard!
この アホが！
先生！
Sensei!
（作業員２）ケッ 人のことより
てめえの心配しろっての
Forget about him! It's yourself that
you should be worrying about!
（作業員３）
おい そんなやつ 後回しだ
Hey! We can deal with him later!
We have to cut that arm loose!
アームを切り離さないと
Damn...
（作業員２）チェッ…
（ギガルト）ぬあああ ううっ…
この じゃじゃ馬が ああっ
Behave yourself,
you piece of...
うう…
ああ…
（ハチマキ）
先生… ギガルト先生…
Sensei! Gigalt Sensei!
聞こえ… ますか？
今すぐ 助けに…
Do you read me?!
We'll come get you!
あっ フィー 早く戻れよ
戻れっつってんだ
Fee! Get back there quick!
Get back there!
Don't make such
a fuss, Hachi.
（ギガルト）騒ぐなよ ハチ
フッ ローランド先生 先生も…
Roland Sensei...
You too, huh?
（電子音）
（タナベ）
ギガルトさん 大丈夫ですか？
Gigalt-san!
Are you okay?
お嬢さん
Little lady?!
Hurry! Grab on!
（タナベ）早く
こっちに つかまってください
Tanabe! I thought I told you
to stay inside!
タナベ 出てくんなって言ったろ？
何様だよ お前は
Who do you think
you are?!
（タナベ）正義のデブリ屋です
A debris hauler
of justice!
はあ？
（タナベ）
悪のデブリ屋は見過ごせません
We can't let those evil debris haulers
get away with this! Right, Senpai?!
そうでしょ？ 先輩
（ハチマキ）
何だよ その悪とか正義とかって
What's with this good
and evil crap?
大事なことです
It's important!
（ハチマキ）何言ってんだ お前
What the hell are
you talking about?
Anyway, once you drop off Sensei
back at Toy Box, come get me!
ともかく 先生をToyBox(トイボックス)に届けて
すぐ降りてこい
（タナベ）はい できるかぎり早く
Understood. I'll get there
as soon as I can.
（ハチマキ）速攻だ ユー コピー？
ASAP! You copy?!
（タナベ）あっ アイ コピー
I copy!
（ギガルト）フッ
（警告音）
（フィー）
ヤバい アームが切られる
Oh, crap! They've cut
through the arm!
反転 出力 上げて
Roll us!
Increase output!
（ユーリ）
オーバーヒートです 追えません
We're overheating!
We can't pursue.
（フィー）この ボロが！
You piece of junk!
（ハチマキ）うっ くっ うう…
くっ… あっ
（作業員１）
ヘッヘッヘッ… 待たせたな
Sorry to keep you waiting.
（作業員２）動けねえんだ
ゆっくり料理してやる
He can't move. Let's cook
this guy nice and slow.
（ハチマキ）くっ 上等だ！
Come get some! Lemme show you what
a debris hauler of justice is made of!
正義のデブリ屋が
どれだけのもんか 見せて…
あっ くっ うっ…
（作業員たちの笑い声）
（作業員たち）おっ？
（隊員）こちらは軌道保安庁
巡視船 クレスタ53です
This is Orbital Security Agency
patrol vessel Cresta-53.
定期航路における…
All unauthorized traffic in established shipping
lanes is subject to boarding and inspection.
（船長）
くっ 手間取り過ぎたか
We took too long, huh?
Heave to immediately and obey
all instructions from this vessel.
（作業員３）だあっ
I say again,
This is Orbital Security Agency patrol vessel Cresta-53.
（作業員３）くそっ
（作業員４）ちゃらあ
Son of a...
Bastards!
（作業員３）うらあーっ おおっ！
ううっ… あっ うう…
うおおっ
（隊長）全員 抵抗をやめろ
これ以上の抵抗は―
Cease any and
all resistance.
Offer any further resistance, and we
will be allowed to use deadly force.
我々に 武器使用の権利を
与えることになる
（作業員５）くっ… うっ…
分かったよ
All right, all right...
（口笛）
さすが
Impressive.
（隊長）ご協力 感謝します
Thank you for
your cooperation.
あなた１人ですか？
大した腕ですね
Are you here by yourself?
This is some impressive work.
つかまってただけだよ
We just held 'em for you,
that's all.
あんたこそ さすがは
保安庁の隊長さんってとこか
Judging from those moves, you must
be an OSA commander or something.
Senpai! Are you okay?
（ハチマキ）ああ
正義の味方が来てくれたからな
Yeah, the cavalry
came to the rescue.
（ギガルト）
すまんな ハチマキ 遅くなった
Sorry we took so long,
Hachimaki.
（ハチマキ）先生
Sensei!
（隊長）えっ…
先生もいらっしゃったのですか？
Sensei? You're here, too?
（ハチマキ）あ…
（ギガルト）おおっ ハキムか
Is that you, Hakim?
（ハキム）はい
そうか 保安指導月間でしたね
Yes, sir.
Oh, now I see. It's Security
Instruction Month, isn't it?
ついでに教え子の様子を見にな
I also dropped in to see how an
old student of mine was doing.
君も先生に？
Sensei taught you, too?
You, too?
あんたも？ あっ…
よろしく ハキム･アシュミードだ
Nice to meet you.
I'm Hakim Ashmead.
Hoshino Hachirota.
I'm a debris hauler.
星野(ほしの)八郎太(はちろうた)
デブリ屋だ
（ギガルト）いいもんだな
This is a fine
sight to see.
（ハチマキ）あ…
（ハキム）ん？
教え子が協力して
１つの仕事をやってのける
Two of my pupils worked together
to see a single job through.
これで俺も安心して
引退できるというものだ
This means I can retire now
and not have to worry.
（ハキム）まだ早いですよ 先生
It's a little early
for that, Sensei.
You don't plan on retiring,
and you know it.
引退する気なんてないくせに
バレたか
Caught me, huh?
宇宙にいる以上
死ぬまで引退はない
When you're in space, you don't retire
until you die. Remember that.
覚えておけ
（ハキム･ハチマキ）アイ コピー
I copy.
- I copy.
（フィー）帰還予定は
120分以上 遅れそうです
Our return ETA will be more than
120 minutes behind schedule.
（クレア）
では 150分後に ５th(フィフス)で接舷
We'll see you in Bay Five
in 150 minutes, then.
事後処理は
保安庁の指示に従ってください
Please follow the OSA's instructions
for follow-up paperwork.
報告書の提出は 本日中に
Submit your report by
the end of the day.
負傷者はいないんですね？
No one was injured,
correct?
（フィー）ああ あと
星野航宙士が事情聴取されています
No. Oh, and Astronaut Hoshino
is having his statement taken.
事情聴取って
どれくらいかかるんですか？
How long does it usually take
for them to take your statement?
余計なこと言わなきゃ
10分で終わる
If you don't mouth off to the officer,
you're done in 10 minutes.
フフッ 先輩のことだから
30分はかかりますね
Knowing Senpai, it'll probably
be more like 30, then.
取れました
（ギガルト）うん
Okay, got it.
ありがとう エンジェル
Thank you, Angel.
えっ エンジェルって
ひょっとして 私のあだ名ですか？
Huh? Angel?
You mean that's
my nickname?
いつまでも
お嬢さんってわけにはいくまい
I can't keep calling you
"little lady," can I?
あ… ありがとうございます
Oh... Thank you.
でも エンジェルは
ちょっと年齢的にも…
But "angel" might not be appropriate
for someone my age...
Oh, you don't like it?
In that case, how about...
ほう 気に入らんか？ だったら…
（せき込み）
はっ…
ギガルトさん さっきの戦いで…
Gigalt-san!
Were you hurt in the fight?!
いや いいんだ ケガじゃない
No, I'm okay...
I wasn't hurt.
でも…
（ギガルト）ガンだよ
But...
It's cancer.
えっ
宇宙に長くいるとな
こういうことも多い
This kind of thing happens a lot when
you're out in space a long time.
（タナベ）そんな…
I don't believe it...
It's already progressed
too far to be treatable.
もう 治らないところまで来ている
だから 黙っていてくれ
So I want you to keep this to yourself.
あいつには
Don't tell him.
♪～
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
♪グッと水を飲み干し
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪今日も一日が終わって
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
A Sky of Stardust
ユーリってさ―
You stare out the window
and zone out sometimes.
たまにボーッと
外 見てるよな
Do you see something
out there?
何か見えるのか？
（ユーリ）
ああ 宇宙が見えます
Yes. I see space.
やった 10分 切った
I did it! I broke ten minutes!
10分
切れるようになりました
I can do it in under
ten minutes now...
（ユーリ）大切な人が
いなくなるとね―
When you lose
someone you love,
悲しくも
つらくもないんですよ
...there's no sadness,
and there's no grief.
えっ
（ユーリ）
何にもないんです
You don't feel
anything at all.
気持ちが
Yuri!
（ハチマキ）ユーリ！